WWW.MY-SUBS.CO
Tell me the worst, Billy.
I'm afraid Mr Rogers beat you
by three-and-a-half seconds.
Take it like a man, Henry. Can I
help it if I am your superior?
You want a drink?
- Why not?
- See you there. Thanks, Billy.
- Well, this is very nice.
- What is?
Mary's beau, Henry
Talbot, has invited us all
to watch him drive at
Brooklands next week.
- He's just sucking up.
- Mama won't ever let you go.
- I don't see why not.
- Because you're still convalescing.
I only want to watch the
race, not drive in it.
It's a long way, and it won't
last much more than ten minutes.
He told me he's inviting Bertie Pelham.
- Oh.
- What about you, Mary?
I think I've talked myself into it,
although I'm sure I'll be sorry.
Just think! It's finished
and open for business.
You are the owner of a
bed-and-breakfast hotel.
- What have you had done?
- I turned a bedroom into a bathroom
- and I've installed an inside privy.
- Think of that.
It leaves me two bedrooms to let,
and one for my niece to run it.
- Which is yours when the time comes.
- Mmm, when the time comes.
All you need now are some clients
and that will happen soon enough.
- How's life for the newly-weds?
- Fine.
Only, Mr Carson wants to
dine at the cottage again.
No need to sound so gloomy.
I can rustle up something.
Whatever you do rustle up,
I won't cook it right, or
the plates will be cold,
- or the dressing will be wrong.
- Does he appreciate all you do?
- Does any man?
- Ooh, Daisy.
Mr Dawes has been given a
date by the examining board.
- Blimey, when is it?
- The 20th.
Oh, my God!
I will thank you not to take
the name of the Lord in vain.
I hope it's not in vain! I
need all the help I can get!
- Do you enjoy weddings?
- Yes. But I'm not going to that one.
I'd feel like the wicked fairy at
the christening of Sleeping Beauty.
Why would Larry Grey want you to
be there? I mean, you of all people.
I'm sure he doesn't. Dickie
must've persuaded them to ask me.
I doubt that. He wouldn't want
to subject you to more insults.
Well, who then?
I'd say this is the
work of Miss Cruikshank.
She's the one always
making a show of friendship.
Why don't I pay a call on her?
See if I can winkle out the truth.
- I'm sorry I showed it to you now.
- Oh, don't be, don't be.
Are things going well
in my former kingdom?
Cora is settling in. I
know it must feel awkward.
Oh, no. I'm yesterday, she's
tomorrow. That's the way it is.
- You must be feeling very hurt.
- Well,
the fact is, I might as well be honest.
I am angry at the way I have been treated.
I don't blame you.
While angry, I say things some
people find hard to forgive.
So, I have decided to go away.
I'd rather vent my rage
on the desert air...
.. and return when I've
regained control of my tongue.
Your self-knowledge is
an example to us all.
You don't think I'm wrong?
The last thing you need
at this stage in your life
is to quarrel with your
son and daughter-in-law.
Precisely. But don't fear. I'll call
on Miss Cruikshank before I leave.
I suspect she's quite a tough nut.
And I'm quite a tough nutcracker.
How's Mr Mason getting on? I'm
always ready if he needs any help.
I'm going down there this afternoon,
I'll tell him you said so.
I am trying to find a
position, Mr Carson, honestly.
I don't say you're not, but it doesn't seem
quite fair on His Lordship to string it out.
Does that mean I'm sacked?
It means I shall be pleased
when we learn the identity
of your next employer, Mr Barrow.
We'd stay with Rosamund, drive
to the track, have lunch,
see some racing and come
home the following day.
It's so unnecessary in your state.
But I'm not in a state. Unless
it's a state of boredom.
Please let me.
- It's not my decision.
- If you mean that, then we're going.
- Edith?
- Oh, I'm in if Bertie's coming.
It's a long way for him.
Maybe there's something
else for him to do in London.
Isn't it enough that
it's a chance to see you?
Would it annoy you if it were?
I'm sorry if Mr Carson
spoke harshly just now.
He doesn't mean to be unkind.
But it worries him when a plan is delayed.
The plan being my departure.
You just haven't found the
right person yet, Mr Barrow.
But I'm sure there are friends
out there waiting for you,
and a new job in a new house
may help you to find them.
Well, you see, Mrs Hughes,...
.. this is the first place I've found
where I've laid down some roots.
I'm terribly sorry, Lady Grantham.
No-one told me you were coming
- and I'm afraid Lord Merton's out.
- It's you I've come to see.
How flattering.
- May I offer you anything?
- Only your attention.
Shall I sit here?
Now, Mrs Crawley tells me
that you paid her a visit
when you first came, that
you were amazingly friendly.
- Well, I hope I'm always friendly.
- Nobody's always friendly.
And now you have invited
her to your wedding,
which has taken her by surprise.
You mean Larry and Mrs Crawley have
not seen eye to eye in the past.
Larry Grey has spoken to
Mrs Crawley in a manner
that in any other century would
have resulted in him being
called out and shot.
I can't believe it was as bad as that.
Then you are misinformed.
But I want to know this.
Why encourage Mrs Crawley when your
fiance detests the mere idea of her?
I still dispute that, but I would say
that Larry had perhaps not
quite thought matters through.
- Meaning?
- Only that his father is old,
and alone, and in need of...
In need of care?
Which you are not prepared to give.
I would've said a companion.
Which you are not prepared to be.
And what of this house? Will you
surrender it to be free of him?
She won't want to live at
Cavenham after Lord Merton's death.
It would be lonely for a woman like her.
But, by heaven, I bet it won't be
too lonely for a woman like you.
I expect they'll have to drag you
out as you break your fingernails
catching at the door case.
So, there we have it.
You want a free nurse to take her
tiresome old man off your hands.
You're a cruel, little Miss, aren't you?
I'd feel sorry for Larry, if
I didn't dislike him so much.
I shall forget you said
that, but you should go now.
Much more, and we may
feel awkward when we meet.
- Which we are bound to do.
- I think not, Miss Cruikshank.
Not if I see you first.
Er, as you may have gathered,
the family will be away
for three days next week,
so if any of you feel
you're owed some time off,
perhaps you could take it then.
Er, but clear it with me first.
I've put in the advertisement.
It'll be out in the morning.
- So, now you just have to be patient.
- What's this?
Mrs Patmore is ready for her first
visitors to the guest house.
- That was quick.
- Yeah, just what I said.
- I've got butterflies.
- Oh, don't be silly.
I'll go over to check it
all when they're in London.
Oh, I'll come with you if you like.
Everyone has something to do
on their free days, except me.
We know what you've got to do, Mr Barrow.
Yes, Mr Carson.
Well! If that doesn't
just take the biscuit.
Are you going to tell me or not?
She's only decided to up sticks and
set sail for the South of France.
- When? - The family
are in London next week
for the racing, so she wants
to leave while they're away.
- She can't do that!
- No?
Well, perhaps you'll pop up and tell her.
- Save me packing.
- What happens to you?
What do you think? I go with her.
I don't know -- strolling
along the Croisette,
dining in Juan-les-Pins.
- It's a burden I can bear.
- And what about me?
You stay here, sticking in stamps.
And so, she's going to sneak off
while they're away from home?
My Lady doesn't sneak,
thank you very much.
If there's any sneaking to
be done, I'll leave it to you.
Must go. So much to do.
It's a nuisance, but I can't help it.
Two dinners, neither very grand,...
- .. and clothes for Brooklands.
- Very good, My Lady.
I'm sorry if you're not keen. I am.
I just worry about getting
Mr Talbot's hopes up.
Well, I'm curious about the fellow.
Listen, I like him a lot, but I
don't believe a professional driver
with very little to look
forward to will make her happy.
Sybil, maybe. But not Mary.
Well, that's the whole point.
What's he got that fascinates Mary
when poor old Tony's rolling acres
and glistening coronet didn't.
You'll say sex-appeal, but
isn't Mary too sensible?
We have a very contrary daughter.
Anyway, I've never been motor racing.
Mr Talbot will fix it. You
can help with the picnic,
but you'll have to take the train.
There won't be any room in the cars.
Mr Bates is looking forward to it.
- I wish I was.
- You don't have to go, you know.
I think I do. It's part of
him, and I must get used to it.
That sounds serious.
I suppose you don't approve.
- It's not for me to say, m'lady.
- But do you approve?
Mr Talbot seems a nice gentleman.
I'm just not sure his life
and your life fit together.
- I don't mean to offend you, m'lady.
- I'm not offended.
I'm troubled because I
understand what you mean.
- They do say that opposites attract.
- Yes, they attract.
But do they live happily ever after?
I think I'll go up in a minute.
How do you revise if he's
testing your general knowledge?
Surely, you'll either
know it or you won't.
- I just feel I have to do something.
- Is it so important to you?
It's important I don't feel a fool.
- You're not a fool. I'm the fool.
- Why do you say that?
Because I still can't decide
what to do about Coyle.
I don't know why not.
Maybe if I'd given evidence in
court, but that never happened
and as Her Ladyship said,
"The story feels unfinished."
You sound as if you're going.
I need to be sure he has
no power over me any more.
Will you tell me when you decide?
When Daisy said you'd like to help,
I wondered if you could bring
the books up to date a bit.
Or tackle some of the heavy stuff?
Oh, there's nothing I can't do
until we separate the piglets.
But I've got to get on top of
the figures. When can you come?
I'm busy just now, as it happens.
Oh, well. Let me know
when you can get away.
You're leaving now? Today?
I'll spend tonight in London,
then I'll sail on the SS Paris
from Southampton tomorrow.
We'll cruise around the Mediterranean,
then I'm staying with
the Broughams in Cannes.
- They keep asking me.
- Surrounded by foreigners.
My reason for travelling is to
make myself eager to come home.
A month among the French should manage it.
- Won't Robert be hurt?
- Oh.
Not as hurt as he would be
if he knew why I was going.
Now, can you give this
to him when they get home?
What if they want to contact
you while you're away?
Well, I've... I've written to Tom.
Told him how to reach me.
He's the most sensible.
Oh, by the way,
I called on Miss Cruikshank.
And was she behind that odd invitation?
The fact is, she wants you
to take Dickie off her hands
and out of her hair.
I'd say your choice is
harder now than before.
You know, when we talked, you
didn't want to come between
- a father and his sons.
- Well, what's changed?
Well, now you must decide
whether to abandon him to his
selfish and greedy children.
I mean, is that kind or right?
It's still a tug-of-war I
have no wish to be part of.
Well, my guess is, when you
take delivery from Miss Amelia
you'll be lucky if you
see a Christmas card.
- Can you be ready by tomorrow night?
- Oh, it's just one couple.
Well, the house has been
beautifully finished.
No doubt about that.
But there is a lot to think about.
You don't offer dinner, do you?
No, if they need dinner,
they can go to the pub.
But I would like to make
a thing of my breakfasts.
- I want a reputation for them.
- You'll manage that easily enough.
I'm here again tomorrow,
but should I come back
on Thursday morning?
The family will still be in London,
and Daisy could easily do the
servants' hall breakfast.
I have no objection.
Now, dinner with Mr Carson. Why not
tomorrow night when they're away?
I suppose we could eat at
a normal time, for once.
Ah, well, you could and you couldn't,...
.. because I've had an idea.
- Oh, hello, stranger.
- I'm not really here.
I'm racing at Brooklands tomorrow,
and I thought I'd pop in
- and see what's new.
- Not much.
Oh, although, we have had an offer today.
I was going to ask you what you thought.
Er, her name is Miss Cassandra Jones.
She thinks we ought to
have an advice column.
- With her dispensing it?
- Yes, but I must say
her samples are quite funny.
"Your husband is losing interest?
Well, here's step one.
Take a look in the mirror."
What are you proposing?
We'll invent some problems,
she can write the answers,
then see how the public likes it.
There's nothing new in an
agony column, of course,
but they're very popular in America,
which means they're due a revival here.
Should we interview her?
No, let's leave it until
we decide to go forward.
I think it's worth a try.
I've never seen motor racing close up.
My sister's new boyfriend
drives. Why not come?
- I'm not sure I should.
- Well, I'm your employer,
so if I think it's all
right then it must be.
You can meet my family,
if you're strong enough.
Looking round the table,
I wonder if we ought to have opened
Grantham House. I feel rather guilty.
Oh, don't. I know what a palaver it is.
More so, now there's no real staff.
Almost everyone we know is
selling their London house.
But I suppose that's not for me to say.
I went past the site of
Devonshire House on my way home.
There's something vast
going up in its place.
Flats and offices and salerooms.
People don't want vast palaces any
more, even if they can afford them.
They were fun, though.
In my youth, all the great hostesses
used to have luncheon
laid for 20 every day.
And if you turned up in time, you
just sat down to a lovely feed.
I'm so sorry, Lady Rosamund, I
thought dinner would be finished.
And so it should be. We'll go through.
Unless the boys prefer to
stay and talk racing cars.
- I think I'd rather join the
ladies. - Like Lord Byron? - Hmm.
Well done for rounding them
all up. I'm very grateful.
Don't be. I'm as keen as you are.
It's a bit obvious. Dropping
in uninvited after dinner.
I hope it is obvious. Obvious that
I want to be a part of this family.
Don't I have a say in the matter?
I want to surround you with people
murmuring, "Isn't he divine?"
Or "You'd be mad to let him go."
Suppose they say, "I shouldn't
have thought a racing driver
was your sort of thing at all"?
They don't have to,
you've already said it.
I'm afraid there's a list as
long as your arm of people
- who are coming tomorrow.
- Hmm.
Just give me the list
and I'll sort it out.
Did you mind my inviting your
family without telling you?
I'm here, aren't I?
Let's get some coffee.
Are you prepared for your exams?
- I've done as much as I'm able.
- No-one can say more.
I confess, I wasn't always sure about it,
but now you've got there, well done.
I wish you every good fortune.
I wonder where she'll go from here.
Doesn't Gwen's visit show us that
in the new century anything is possible?
And what about you, Mr
Molesley, are you ready?
I think so, hmm. Ready as I'll ever be.
I'll walk down with some lunch
for you and Daisy and Mr Dawes.
- Oh, you don't have to.
- No, I'd like to.
I'll give you a hand.
Mr Barrow, what are you doing
with your free time tomorrow?
Scanning the jobs column,
Mrs Hughes, what else?
There, that's got it.
I think you're all set.
- It's a good car.
- Clearly, we need you on the team.
Don't tempt me, Henry.
- Who's this?
- Laura Edmunds, my editor.
Laura, this is Tom
Branson, my brother-in-law,
and the man of the hour, Mr Henry Talbot.
- Hello.
- My sister, Mary.
These are my parents. You can
sort them out in your own time.
- Nice to meet you at last.
- Lord Grantham, Lady Grantham.
This is Charlie Rogers.
He drives on Henry's team.
Henry's team, is it? When I beat
him into a cocked hat every time.
Oh, he's just showing off. I'm
faster, I'm younger and better.
But not at driving.
I wish there was something
more I could do to be useful.
- Oh, just cheer, Tom.
- I don't have to be asked.
I don't know why I'm doing
this. I can't even swallow.
It's all terribly swank, not
a bit what we're used to.
- No? - Normally, it's an oil-stained
sandwich and a bottle of pop.
Well, I'm glad to think
we've brought an improvement.
Thank you.
My train sat in a tunnel for an hour.
Anyway, I'm here now.
Come and meet Miss Edmunds.
Is it hard to be a woman editor?
Fleet Street sounds so very tough.
It's hard to be a woman
anything if it isn't domestic.
- But I do my best.
- I think it's courageous and good.
Heavens! Papa's conversion to the
modern world is almost complete.
Don't be deceived. He'd still like
to see us happy wives and mothers.
That's not fair. Even leopards
can change some of their spots.
Quite. Now, there's still some food.
I'm glad no-one seems unhappy
that Lady Edith hired a woman.
You're a big improvement on the
last editor, that's for sure.
And you're not the only one around
here who's broken a few barriers.
I started my life at Downton
Abbey as the chauffeur.
I think we're being summoned.
- The cars are in place. We should go.
- Right behind you.
You'll stay there if I have my way.
I can't begin to tell you what it
means to me that you came today.
I hope so, because my digestive
system has packed up completely.
I'm going to be fine. Mary, you
must credit me with SOME skill.
Now, when I pass you, I expect
to see you cheer and wave.
Does praying count?
- Henry!
- Coming.
Well, that should keep my spirits up.
I'll see you in a minute.
'We're just waiting for the last chap...'
'And here he comes. It's Henry
Talbot, driving car No.14.'
Good luck, Charlie.
Good luck, old boy.
'Now, any moment,
the flag will fall and
the race will begin.'
'Just listen to the roar of those
engines, ladies and gentlemen.'
And they're off. There they
go, tearing down the street
and jostling for first position.
Come on, Charlie!
Here they come!
Come on, Talbot!
I don't think you can shout that.
Isn't Talbot the name of a car?
I can't shout "Come on, Henry."
They might all be called Henry.
- Oh, my God, here they are.
- Come on!
- When will it be over?
- Not soon, they go round and round.
Yes! Come on!
Come on! God bless you! Come on!
What's the point? What
do they get out of it?
What do you think? Speed.
This is kind of you, Mrs Patmore.
I meant to bring some lemonade, but
I left it on the kitchen table.
I could kick meself.
Is this what you mean?
Oh, that was kind of you,
Mr Barrow. Thank you.
How were the exams? Did you do well?
We can't know the answer
to that, can we, Mr Dawes?
You'll find out soon enough.
But Daisy will have to wait a while.
I've not finished yet. I've got
three more papers after lunch.
- Was it harder than you thought?
- See for yourself.
What about number two? It knocked
me for a loop, I can tell you.
What does it say? Read it out, Andy.
- I'll read it.
- Why, what's the matter?
"Tsar...
"Nic... holas..."
Here, give it here.
"Tsar Nicholas I called Turkey
'the sick man of Europe'.
What were the causes of Turkey's illness
and what measure was the Russian
Tsar prescribing for its recovery?"
I can't read, Mr Molesley.
At least Mr Barrow's been
trying to teach me to read,
- but I'm too stupid to learn.
- Don't say that.
So, there we have it. I'm
a fool who knows nothing.
I am nothing.
'The race is going to hot up now
because the lead car,
car No.6, has withdrawn
with what looks like
radiator trouble. Oh, dear.
It looks like Sir Patrick
has blown a gasket too!'
Here they come again.
- My God, but don't you envy them?
- No, I don't.
Nor me. We're going to
have to keep an eye on Tom.
There is something gallant and
daring in it, even I can see that.
Andy, maybe I can help,
if you'd like me to.
Oh, that's very kind.
What do you say, Andy?
Well, I've tried and tried with Mr
Barrow, and I can't break through.
- I'm too stupid.
- Will you stop saying that?
You're not stupid, and I promise you I
can soon have you reading for pleasure.
If you'll just come two or three
times a week after school closes.
- Could you manage that?
- That's the best time for me.
It won't take long, you'll see.
- We can go on with...
- Mr Barrow,
it might be better if you step back now.
You've been very generous, but we wouldn't
want to confuse Andy with different methods.
No, of course not.
I hate to cut this short, but Daisy's
still got a lot of work to do
- and she better get started.
- Need any help?
- I can manage.
- Well, good luck, Daisy.
Yes, good luck.
Funny when the house is
empty above decks and below.
All the more reason for us to be vigilant.
- Let's sit down.
- Erm, I don't know.
Oh, just for a moment.
- Hmm.
- There.
That's nice, isn't it?
They don't live badly,
you have to concede.
They live as they're supposed
to live. It has its burdens
and its benefits.
Better than a life of just burden.
I hope you're ready for tonight.
For once, we can eat when civilised
people eat, so don't be late back.
Are you sure you know how to cook it?
Don't you worry. I've been through
every detail with Mrs Patmore.
Hello.
What have we here?
- Can anyone join in?
- No, Mr Barrow, they cannot.
'It's shaping up to be a tight
battle for the winner's laurels.
What's this? The No.8
Bentley is slowing down!
It's pulled in at the side of the track.
Looks like steering trouble.
And there goes Rogers!
Rogers has taken the lead and now look!
Henry Talbot in car No.14 tries
to snatch the lead away from him.
Here he comes again!
Talbot attacking from the inside
and challenging for the lead.
I don't think Rogers has
the power to fight him off!
Oh, dear, look! Rogers
is coming back at him!
Would you believe it? He's
going to take back the lead!
What a stunning piece of
driving by Charles Rogers!'
And here they come again,
it's the two Bentleys
neck and neck past the
grandstand. Come on, Bentley boys!
Come on!
Chin up. Won't be long now.
Really? It feels as if we're
trapped in some witch's curse
for all eternity.
'This is terrible. This is awful!'
- Stay here. Bertie, come with me.
- Of course.
No, it's no good. I can't stay.
You're not going anywhere.
- I must go to her!
- No, no, Anna. Not in your condition.
- Never mind, I have to go.
- Can you follow her, please?
Of course.
Get him out of there!
Charlie!
- Turn around!
- Charlie!
It's too late. Henry, Henry, get back!
Henry, Henry, get back!
- Charlie!
- He's gone, Henry.
No! Charlie!
Charlie!
We have to help him. Charlie!
- Charlie!
- Let me pass.
I know him. Let me pass!
You can't say that. We
don't know it's him.
- Oh, my God.
- I need help here!
Who is it? Can we find out who
it is? Tom, Bertie, who is it?
I'm afraid it's Charlie Rogers.
He was my friend.
My best friend, really.
If that phrase didn't sound
like it was something from a...
.. Rider Haggard novel.
I keep asking myself
if I... encouraged him.
Of course you encouraged him,
- and he encouraged you.
- Yes, but I'm so stupid, I...
I...
I needled him and I
teased him, I pushed him.
And he did the same.
And if you'd have died instead of him,
he'd be here asking exactly
the same questions.
Yes, but I didn't die and he did!
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
We're going now.
Aunt Rosamund doesn't want
to cancel dinner tonight.
She thinks we should all be
together on a day like today.
I can't. I have to deal
with Charlie's family.
Of course. I wasn't thinking.
Tell her thank you.
- And, Mary...
- No.
Let's not do any of that stuff now.
Go on, then. Put us out of our
misery. Did he pass or not?
Mr Molesley, I'd be very glad
if you would join the teaching
staff at the village school.
Well, I'll be...
Very good of you to come
up tonight to tell me.
Does that mean you'll be a
teacher and not a servant?
- When will you be leaving?
- Give him a moment.
There's a lot to be settled.
- Course there is.
- I'm impressed, Mr Molesley.
There are Oxford and Cambridge
graduates who know far less than you.
You should be proud.
Good night.
Mr Dawes.
Thank you very much.
Well done, Mr Molesley.
- It'll be you next.
- I doubt it, but thanks.
We should celebrate. Come into the
kitchen while I get the dinner going.
There's a bottle of wine there,
if Mr Carson wouldn't mind.
Is that the end of service for you?
Hmm, service is ending
for most of us, Daisy.
I've just got a head start.
Will you miss it?
Oh, let's face it. I were
never going to make butler.
Well, not in a proper house like this one.
And from now on, there's going
to be more and more people
chasing fewer and fewer
jobs, so it's probably time.
And this seemed like a good way to go.
Well, I'm glad. You deserve it.
I never think I deserve anything.
Perhaps I've been wrong all along.
Are you coming, Mr Barrow?
In a minute. You go ahead.
Here you are, Daisy, you have one.
- Andy, come on. Have a glass of wine.
- Congratulations.
But how did you do it?
Er, I must have stumbled and
fallen over in the wrong way.
Mrs Patmore put on a bandage, but I'll go to
the doctor in the morning if it's no better.
- But how are you going to cook?
- I can't cook!
I can't lift.
But it's not difficult. I'll
talk you through it, don't worry.
You mean... I'm going to cook?!
It's very straightforward.
Now, get the chicken
in the oven right away,
then peel the potatoes and
prepare the cauliflower.
Oh, and put a kettle on to boil.
You should find bread and an
onion for the bread sauce.
Butter and milk are in
the meat safe outside.
I assume that none of us are
going to eat anything else.
One talks of risk and danger,
and it sounds like fun.
But of course, the reality
behind it is sudden death.
Sudden, stupid, wasteful death.
It was a bloody awful business.
A bloody, bloody awful business.
- The English language never
lets you down. - Oh, shut up!
Shall we go through?
- You're going to bed.
- Me, too.
The rest of you can talk
into the small hours.
Should I say goodbye?
Not yet. Come into the
drawing room for a drink.
Henry's on the telephone.
Tell him to ring tomorrow.
I think you should speak to him.
'You should try to sleep.'
I found that I had to
hear your voice first.
The truth is...
.. I won't sleep until I
know where we're headed.
Henry, please let's not do this now.
- Think of Charlie, not us.
- Hear me out. Charlie would have.
Because his death has made me realise
we don't have a minute
to waste, you and I.
This is my carpe diem moment. I...
- I must seize the day.
- No.
- What do you mean?
- I'm sorry, I wouldn't have said this now,
but today has made me
realise something, too.
We're not meant to be together, Henry.
- We're not right.
- I can...
Don't start saying you'll give up racing.
I don't want you to give up anything
- except me.
- I can't give you up.
Please. I wish you nothing but good.
I want you to have a long and happy life.
- Just not with me.
- Mary, please don't do this.
I must.
Good night, Henry.
I wish you wouldn't.
Do you know the worst thing?
When they said it was Charlie
and not Henry who was dead, I was glad!
Think of that. I was glad!
You're not seeing straight.
Today brought up Matthew's
death and all the rest of it.
- You're in a black mist.
- It's not what I want!
You're frightened of being hurt again.
But let me tell you this.
You will be hurt again, and so will I,
because being hurt is part of being alive.
But that is no reason to give up
on the man who is right for you.
I'm sorry I'm a bit behind.
The potatoes may have caught.
Never mind. Er, how's the cauliflower?
Oh, God.
Oh, while you're there,
put in the apple crumble. Bottom oven.
Mmm.
I think it's been a good day.
The funny thing is, I quite
enjoyed it in the end.
I'm glad it's turned out
well for Mr Molesley.
And Andy. I think that'll
turn out well an' all.
I suppose so. Even if he only wants to read
to learn more about farming from Mr Mason.
And if he does? You must share, Daisy.
Love isn't finite. If Mr
Mason makes new friends,
it doesn't mean he has
any less love for you.
Doesn't it?
I never had much that
was my own, you know.
Well, you found the love of a father
there and you can count on him.
Just as you can count on me.
Now, run along and I'll finish this.
Mmm. This crumble's good.
My mother's was always a bit soggy.
Hmm, crumble. Oh!
Is that it now? Are we done?
Oh, just put the things in to soak.
Make sure you cover the pots with water.
You don't have to do the washing up
till tomorrow if you don't want to.
- You won't be better by the morning?
- Oh, not for that.
We could ask Billy to come over,
but he's got his own work to do.
You don't mind, do you?
No, I don't mind.
I expect you're glad to
get to bed. I know I am.
- What is it?
- I just wondered if I was right.
That you're to be congratulated.
It's a bit early to
shout about it, but yes.
I'm happy for you. It's good
to think of a new life coming,
especially on a day like this.
Well, good night.
Look at you, stretched out like a pasha.
A creature of leisure.
Early night for me. He went to
bed when he left the dining room.
Not for me. She's very shaken.
- By the crash?
- Because of the crash,
and she's broken up with Mr Talbot.
I wouldn't have thought it was the right
night to make that sort of decision.
She says she's sure.
- Do you think she's right?
- I don't know.
Probably.
Then there's no more to be said.
I'm afraid I've got to go.
You've been such a help.
It's odd, isn't it? We
witnessed a tragedy today
but, sitting here with your arm around me,
I can't remember feeling so comfortable.
When you say things like
that, you make me so happy.
If it isn't wrong to feel
happy on a day like this.
I don't believe it's ever wrong
to feel happy and confident
in someone else's company.
Do I really make you feel those things?
It's not a trap.
Today has been sad and wretched,
and having you here has
helped me face it, that's all.
The thing is, I'd like
to be trapped, and...
Well, I better just say it.
I want to marry you.
- Oh!
- You're not offended?
Offended? Why would I be offended?
I'm thrilled, I'm delighted.
- I'm just rather surprised.
- Why? You know I'm mad about you.
I don't ever think I'm the
sort of girl men are mad about.
Then you're wrong, because I am.
I... I know I've not got much to offer
and your father's probably hoping for
more than a penniless land agent,
but if love is allowed
to weigh in the balance,
I've got plenty of that.
I must ask you something.
Would you let me bring Marigold with me?
Marigold?
Your family's ward?
You see, I'm much fonder
of her than anyone else,
and I'd hate to leave her behind.
If she means that much to you.
Of course, I hope we'll
have children of our own
- before close of play.
- Oh, absolutely. I'd like that, too.
- Does that mean you accept?
- Not quite.
I'll have to think about it. I'm
sorry to be a killjoy, but I must.
Be my guest. I'm not going
to marry anyone else.
Not until after you've
broken my heart, anyway.
I'll go.
Kiss me first.
And I promise I won't
keep you waiting too long.
All right, let's see
what you make of that.
Now, I must be off, but my
niece, Lucy, is in the kitchen.
- She'll see to everything.
- Thank you. - Thank you.
Hello, Carson.
Mrs Crawley is in the library, My Lord.
She's been here for some time.
- Why?
- She didn't say, My Lady,
but she seems eager to see you all.
Also, er, Mr Spratt rang to ask
when you'd be arriving from London.
- Mr Spratt?
- The Dowager Countess' butler.
Oh, that Mr Spratt. What did he want?
- Again, no explanation was proffered.
- Curiouser and curiouser.
Isobel, I hope we haven't
kept you waiting for hours.
Not at all, it's entirely my
fault. I got here far too early.
- How was it?
- Perfectly terrible, as it happens,
but let's not go into that now.
Oh, I am sorry. And, to be quite honest,
- I feel rather awkward.
- Why, what is it?
I have a letter from Cousin Violet.
Why didn't she bring it herself?
- Because she's gone away.
- Gone away? Where?
She's on board the Paris,
headed for the Mediterranean.
This is me, isn't it? I've
done it. She's furious with me.
I don't see the point of
bringing any of that up now.
- What does it say in the letter?
- Nothing much.
She needs a change of air,
and Spratt is bringing a
present by way of goodbye.
That's why he rang.
Mr Spratt has arrived, My Lord.
- Oh, show him in.
- Well, that is,
he's in the servants' hall
with a present for Your Lordship and
he doesn't want to bring it up here.
- What is going on?
- He may be right, My Lord.
- Let's go and see what it is.
- If you wish,
but it all seems very rum to me.
What is it? What's the surprise?
You'll soon see, m'lord,
but I think it's a good one.
- Good day, m'lord.
- Spratt, what is
this great secret you're about to reveal?
Her Ladyship chose her herself,
m'lord. Er, she was most particular.
Oh! Hello, little one!
Oh!
Now, what are we going to call you, eh?
Oh, I know, Tiaa.
I thought we always had
names from ancient Egypt.
Tiaa was a wife of Amenhotep II
and the mother of Thutmose IV.
Don't you know anything?
She's not exactly trained yet, m'lord.
so we decided against
bringing her up to the library.
Oh, I don't care about that.
You're coming upstairs with me.
Tom, what about this, eh?
He does love his dogs.
How were your guests this morning?
Was everything satisfactory?
Oh, very. He was a doctor,
Mrs Hughes. Imagine that!
So, I don't think I could
have started better.
Even if I did work harder
over their breakfast
than anything I've done
since Lady Rose got married.
Oh, talking of which,
has Mr Carson survived his
ordeal from last night?
Put it this way --
he has discovered a new respect for
the role of cook and bottle washer.
So I think he'll be giving
less trouble in the future.
What's so funny?
Just life, Mr Carson.
Just life.
You push in here, into my home,
to call me a grubby little gold-digger?
You've got a nerve.
I wouldn't like to see this family
dragged into a local brouhaha.
He means me.
I'm not as simple as I used to
be. My life is not as simple.
What would they say if they found out
that I was a servant at the big
house? What would their parents say?
I know you. I know you to be a
nasty, jealous, scheming bitch.